Central New York Cultural Ephemera Collection
Central New York Cultural Ephemera Collection
1805-2002
1.5 linear ft.
Miscellaneous printed material and correspondence relating to cultural life in Central New York. Theatres, clubs, musical performances, academic commencements, local politics, sporting events, etc.
2572277
Scope and Contents of the Collection
The Central New York Cultural Ephemera Collection contains miscellaneous printed material and correspondence relating to cultural life in Central New York, including musical and theatrical performances, lectures, clubs and hobbies, academic and sports events, local politics, and more.
Individuals of interest represented in the collection include Israel Zangwill, a Russian Jewish author; Capt. Archibald B. Snow, "actor, author, vocalist, impressionist, humorist and entertainer"; Melville Clark, inventor of the Clark Irish Harp; and Charlie Brown, a local salesman and musician who led his own dance orchestra for many years. Local politicians are also represented, including Averell Harriman, Lee Alexander and James M. Hanley; there are also two items relating to John F. Kennedy.
Among the institutions represented are Hamilton College, Cortland County Teachers' Institute, Madison University (later Colgate University), several local theatres (Empire, Bastable, Crescent, Temple, more) and many more.
Arrangement of the Collection
Folders are arranged alphabetically within each series; Correspondence, Legal documents and programs from the various theaters are arranged chronologically within each folder.
Related Material
See also the following:
Dave Salmon Inc. Collection of Syracuse Cultural Ephemera
Portfolio Club Records
Society for New Music Archive
Syracuse Friends of Chamber Music Records
Nancy Ann White Correspondence
Subject and Genre Headings
New York State; Dance and theatre; Alexander, Lee, -1996.; Brown, Charles F.; Clark, Melville.; Hanley, James M., 1920-2003.; Kennedy, John F. (John Fitzgerald), 1917-1963.; Roddy, Edith J.; Zangwill, Israel, 1864-1926.; Dauber's Club.; Pastime Athletic Club.; Syracuse University Flying Club.; Freemasons -- New York (State); Local government -- New York (State) -- Onondaga County.; Theater -- United States -- History -- 20th century.; Syracuse (N.Y.) -- Societies and clubs.; Cortland (N.Y.) -- Intellectual life -- 20th century.; Ithaca (N.Y.) -- Intellectual life -- 20th century.; Syracuse (N.Y.) -- Intellectual life -- 20th century.; Utica (N.Y.) -- Intellectual life -- 20th century.; Clippings (information artifacts); Correspondence.; Membership cards.; Photographs.; Posters.; Programs (documents); Scrapbooks.; Tickets.
Access Restrictions
The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advanced notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.
Acquisition Information
Core collection of theatre material purchased with funds from Library Associates.
Accruals
Additions to the collection occur on an ongoing but irregular basis.
Inventory
- Correspondence
  - Mattice, A. (Rev.), 1923; 1944; principal of Fort Plain Seminary, Fort Plain, New York (Box 1)
  - Zangwill, Israel, 1923; 1944; author (Box 1)
  - Miscellaneous, 1805-1960 (gaps); includes letter to Nixon from Syracuse resident (Box 1)
- Legal documents
  - Miscellaneous, 1814-1890 (gaps); undated (Box 2)
- Photographs
  - Pastime Athletic Club, 1905; photograph (Oversize 2)
  - Miscellaneous, Syracuse, Manlius Village, Ithaca Conservatory of Music, Utica, Naples, more (Box 1)
- Printed material
  - Academics and sports
    - Miscellaneous, 1862-1923; 2002,; undated (Box 1)
      See also Photographs: Pastime Athletic Club.
  - Music and theatre
    - B. F. Keith's Theatre, 1914; 1923,; undated; programs, postcards (Box 1)
    - Bastable Theatre, circa 1895-1922 (Box 1)
    - Charlie Brown (bands), 1924-1930; 1969; scrapbook of clippings; some correspondence (Box 1)
    - Clark, Melville, 1908; 1910; lecture/concert programs; See also related collections: Melville Clark Papers and Clark Music Company Records. (Box 1)
    - Crescent Theatre, circa 1895-1922 (Box 1)
    - Empire Theatre, 1901-1922 (Box 1)
    - Grand Opera House (H.A. Jacobs) (Oversize 1)
    - Temple Theatre, 1916; 1925,; 1928,; undated (Box 1)
    - Valley Theatre, circa 1910-1915 (Box 1)
    - Wieting Opera House
      - 1892-1914 (Box 1)
      - 1914-1928 (Box 2)
      - Undated (Box 2)
      - Oversize, undated (Oversize 1)
    - Miscellaneous posters, theatre performances (Oversize 1)
    - Miscellaneous posters, theatre performances and circus (Map-case 102)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 2)
  - Politics
    - Alexander, Lee, 1972-1973; 1978; holiday cards, article about (Box 2)
    - Hanley, James M., 1968-1971; campaign material, form letter to supporters, holiday cards (Box 2)
    - Onondaga County Democratic Committee, 1958-1968; includes program from John F. Kennedy Inaugural Ball (1961) and, in the March for Democrats booklet (1964), an "In Memoriam" page; official program book from 1962 New York State Democratic Convention; more (Box 2)
    - Vietnam-era anti-war poster (Oversize 1)
    - Women's Democratic Club, 1964-1970; includes a few manuscript items (Box 2)
    - Miscellaneous, includes a few manuscript items (Box 2)
  - Miscellaneous
    - Onondaga County History Portfolio, series of colored plates on Onondaga County history published by the Onondaga Savings Bank in a portfolio format (Oversize 1)
    - Miscellaneous, includes Oswego Centennial stamps, ribbon from Soldiers and Sailors Memorial dedication, New York State Fair items, much more (Box 2)
    - Miscellaneous, page from Harper's Weekly, "Reaping at Syracuse," text and illustration, 1 August 1857 (Oversize 1)
- Miscellaneous
  - Daubers Club, 1941-1942 (Box 2)
  - Masons / Freemasons, assorted material relating to local Masonic Lodges (Box 2)
  - Syracuse University Flying Club, 1929; correspondence; ticket stubs; printed material; ledger with minutes of the meeting (Box 2)
  - Scrapbook, bound volume; originally held banking accounts, but pages have been pasted over with advertisements, clipping, pictures, etc. (Oversize 2)
  - Miscellaneous (oversize), certificates of appointment (Oversize 1)